POPPY: Coming this fall, Only Murderers In The Building.
前情提要
今年秋季上线 《大楼里只有谋杀犯》
这个创意不错 我写的
- That's very good. I wrote that.
那晚到底发生了什么
- What did happen that night?
凶手捅死了邦尼
MABEL: The killer stabs Bunny, and then leaves
然后从我衣柜后面的洞口离开
through the hole in the bottom of my closet.
邦尼说：“14 萨维奇”
Bunny said, "14 Savage."
克雷普斯就是亮粉男
Kreps is Glitter Guy.
但克雷普斯为什么要杀邦尼呢 是为了得到那幅画吗
CHARLES: But, why would Kreps kill Bunny? I mean, did he want her painting?
你不可能实施这么复杂的谋杀
- There's no way that you can pull off a murder this sophisticated.
- I said that's enough!
我说 够了
如果我真的这么蠢 我怎么能搞定全世界最聪明的女人？
If I'm so stupid,
how come I was able to land smartest woman on the planet?
每天晚上 我都去本地烤肉酒吧 “小鸡查克”
CINDA [podcast]: Every night, I'd go to the local bar and grill, the Chicken Chug.
MABEL: This all has something to do with All Is Not OK In Oklahoma.
这一切都与《俄克拉荷马不太欧克》有关
别再查下去了 你不知道她能干出什么来
POPPY: You should let this go.
You don't know what she's capable of.
你不知道她为了达到目的能干出什么事来
You don't know what she'd do to get what she wants.
说真的吗 一个解开了 贝基·巴特勒失踪和谋杀案的播客主
MABEL: Seriously? You're that terrified of a podcaster who solved
把你吓成这样？
the murder of Becky Butler?
-对 -为什么
- Yes. - Why?
因为我就是贝基·巴特勒
- Because I'm Becky Butler.
犯罪主脑
♪
该死
- Well, shit.
[quiet car driving by] [dog barking, birds chirping]
在我成为整个国家热议的人
SOUTHERN WOMAN: Before I became one of the most talked about people in the country,
贝基·巴特勒之前
Becky Butler, I had a pretty ordinary life.
我过着普通的生活
如果你假设大多数普通人的生活 都很悲惨的话
Ordinary, that is, if you assume most ordinary people are pretty miserable.
[man coughing heavily]
我想这个假设是十分合理的
Which I assume is a pretty safe assumption.
困在艰难的处境中多久才算久呢
CINDA [podcast]: How long is too long to stay in a bad situation?
这是伊丽莎白·戴维斯 在2003年冬天思考的问题
This is what Elizabeth Davies was pondering
in the winter of 2003.
爸爸 我给你做了健康早餐
BECKY: Daddy, I made you a healthy breakfast.
我不饿
- Not hungry.
我觉得如果你吃点东西…
- I think if you got something--
我他妈不饿
- I ain't fucking hungry.
[phone ringing]
迪普顿市长办公室 有什么能帮你的吗
- Mayor Tipton's office. How can I assist you?
是的 当然 请稍等一下
Oh, yes, of course. Just hold on one second.
市长 是您妻子打来的
Sir? It's your wife.
现在没空
- Not now.
♪
[presses button]
很抱歉 他正在开会
- I'm so sorry. He's in a meeting right now.
还有什么能帮你的吗 特蕾莎
Is there anything I can help you with, Theresa?
[glass clink]
[pouring]
市长 如果您没什么事 我准备下班了
Sir, I was gonna get going, unless you need anything.
多待一会 贝基
- Oh, stay a bit, Becky.
跟你的市长喝一杯
Have a drink with your mayor.
- Oh, I should really get going.
我真的该走了
你确定吗
- Are you sure?
我爸爸在等我回家呢 晚安
- Well, my dad's expecting me, so good night.
MAYOR: Well, maybe tomorrow.
那也许明天吧
你不能永远拒绝我
You're not always gonna be able to say no to me.
♪
“我得离开这里”
CINDA [podcast]: "I need to get out of here,"
是伊丽莎白·戴维斯在日记中 写下的最后一句话
were the last words Elizabeth Davies wrote in her journal
但五天之后她的手臂 便在自家邮箱里被发现
only five days before her left hand
was found in her own mailbox.
[click]
[quiet snoring]
[typing]
辛达·坎宁
[clicking]
[typing]
如何消失 让周围的人永远找不到你
如何消失
[click]
[snoring continues]
[snipping]
[echoing slice]
[quiet chatter] -REPORTER: This is Channel 37 News,
37新闻台为您报道贝基·巴特勒的失踪案
reporting on the disappearance of Becky Butler,
切克沙本地人 迪普顿市长的行政组成员
a local Chickasha native and a member
of Mayor Tipton's executive team,
她于上周失踪
who went missing last week. Authorities have no leads
直播 仍在继续寻找失踪女性 KZJP新闻
警方没有任何线索
and are said to be bringing in outside law enforcement help.
据称将借调外部警力协助调查
门没锁
[knocking] - Nope.
打扰了 坎宁女士
- [no accent]: Excuse me, Ms. Canning? - Mm-hmm.
- Um, ma'am...
女士 我叫波比·怀特 我是你的忠实粉丝
My name is Poppy White.
I'm your biggest fan. CINDA: Cute.
波比 这名字真可爱 跟我最爱的贝果同名
Poppy, my favorite bagel. What can I do for you, Poppy?
有什么事吗 波比
我有个故事是很好的播客题材
- Uh, I... I have a story
that I think would be a really good podcast.
是关于俄克拉荷马州一个失踪的年轻女人
[sigh] It's about a young woman
in Oklahoma. She disappeared.
失踪的女孩太多了 波比
- Lot of girls disappear, Poppy.
- Yeah, but, um,
是啊 但她被那个小城镇的市长骚扰了
she was being harassed by the mayor of a small town,
他的竞选标语是“一切都会没事”
and his campaign slogan was, "It's All Gonna Be OK." Um,
寓意俄克拉荷马没事
"OK" as in "Oklahoma,"
所以我想 “俄克拉荷马有事” 这个名字很适合做播客标题
and I thought All Is Not OK In Oklahoma
would be a good title for a podcast.
我喜欢你的风格
- I like your style.
失踪还是死亡？
Missing or dead?
-什么 -那个女孩
- Excuse me? - The girl.
- Missing.
-失踪 -希望她死了
- Well, let's hope she's dead.
如果这个播客想有一线生机的话 我需要她死
For it to even have a chance, I'd really need her dead.
被谋杀是最理想的 被那个市长谋杀的 那就再好不过了
Ideally murdered. Ooh! And by that mayor. That would be amazing.
抱歉 你想要什么
I'm sorry. Uh, what exactly do you want?
我想要一份工作 坎宁女士
- I would like a job, Ms. Canning.
♪
所以当我发现贝基·巴特勒的失踪案时
- So, when I discovered Becky Butler's disappearance,
我的直觉告诉我必须要报道
I just knew that I had to cover it.
我从没想到会引起如此大的反响
Never did I think it would become such a sensation.
但大部分功劳要归功于…波比
But, a lot of the credit really has to go to-- Ooh, Poppy.
是的 辛达
- Yes, Cinda? [laugh]
火鸡三明治 不要生菜和番茄 不要面包
- Turkey sandwich, no lettuce,
no tomato.
No bread. Just some turkey on tinfoil
就一些火鸡肉包在锡纸里 旁边放上一点面包
and a little bread on the side.
Where was I? Oh!
我说到哪了 我觉得“天才”这个词 不足以描绘
I find the term "genius" to be reductive.
答案是 “我们都是蒂姆·科诺”
CHARLES [podcast]: The answer, as it turned out,
we are all Tim Kono. [click]
“我们都是蒂姆·科诺”
- "We are all Tim Kono?"
真有人听这破玩意吗
Are people really listening to this insipid shit?
我需要新的《俄克拉荷马》
I need a new Oklahoma. [rattling]
我不会是昙花一现的真实犯罪播客 波比 我不会的
I will not be the one hit wonder of true crime podcasts, Poppy.
I won't. I will not be... [pills rattling]
我不会成为播客界的五分钱乐队
podcast Nickelback.
你有考虑过我那个罗斯·库伯的创意吗
- Have you given any thought
to my idea about Rose Cooper,
多年前失踪的那个艺术家？
that artist who went missing years ago?
艺术？波比 认真的吗
- Art? Poppy, really?
-你知道什么跟艺术押韵吗 -聪明
Do you know what rhymes with art?
- Smart? - Fart.
放屁 意思是 没人在乎艺术
As in no one gives a flying fart.
[sigh] I need something with famous people, and blood,
我需要名人 鲜血
and, ideally, a hot girl with a great rack.
最好是身材火辣的大胸女孩
天啊 我需要一桩谋杀案 精彩的谋杀案
[pills rattling] God, I need a murder. A good one.
我受够了等待
And I'm tired of waiting for one to fall into my lap.
天啊 你可真没用
God, you are useless!
好吧 我会靠自己打造出这档节目
Fine. I will make this happen all on my fucking own!
[scattering]
♪
-所以波比就是贝基·巴特勒 -对
- So, Poppy is Becky Butler. - Yes,
这意味着辛达把一位市长送进了监狱
which means Cinda sent a mayor to prison
但她明知道他被控杀害的女孩仍然活着
for killing someone she knew was still alive.
- And now, she's trying to top herself
现在她为了保住自己的地位 要让我们替她犯下的谋杀
by sending us to prison for a murder she committed.
去坐牢
天啊 她真厉害
- God, is she good!
怎么了 这个计划很大胆
What? This is so audacious,
you know. I'd wish I thought of it.
真希望我能想出这个点子 真心的
Really. I mean, I wouldn't have gone as far,
我不会做得这么过火 但这种敬业精神 真叫人敬佩
but what commitment, huh?
说真的吗
- Really?
别怪罪玩家 要怪就怪游戏本身 兄弟
- [urban]: Uh, don't blame the player. Blame the game, brah.
不 别这么说
- No. Don't do that. [Mrs. Gambolini squawks]
她一直以来都在我们眼皮子底下
- She was right in front of us all along.
这个故事讲述者兼艺术家 为了走出她播客事业的瓶颈不惜陷害我们
The storyteller artist framing us
to get the hell out of her podcast lane!
但现在我们怎么反击
- But now, how do we get her?
这不是件容易的事 但我有个计划
- It's not gonna be easy,
but I have a plan.
- Ooh. What?
什么计划
抱歉 我以为计划会适时地 浮现在我的脑中
- I'm sorry. I thought a plan would, uh, come to me in that moment,
but, uh, no.
但是 没有 大脑一片空白
Nothing.
不过…
Although...
没有
Oh. No. [bird chattering]
- [sigh] Okay, we have we have a ton on Oklahoma,
好吧 关于俄克拉荷马我们有很多信息 但邦尼的谋杀案？
but on Bunny's murder?
我们知道她跟克雷普斯警探是一伙的
- Well, we know she's working with Detective Kreps.
可是“14 萨维奇”怎么能跟辛达联系起来
- But, how does "14 Savage" relate to Cinda?
我们有那把刀
- We still have the knife,
威廉姆斯警探正在做法医取证
and Detective Williams is running forensics. We just reach out to her.
我们只要找到她…
如果辛达的DNA在那把刀上 那就盖棺定论了
If Cinda's DNA is on that knife, it's game over!
-对 -我这就给威廉姆斯警探发信息
- Okay, I'm gonna text Detective Williams. [beep]
我们要对抗一位非常有才华的播客主
- We find ourselves up against
a very talented storyteller
和一位平庸的警察
and a very mediocre cop.
但我们如何以智取胜呢
But, how do we outwit them? [beep]
-我们需要让他们认罪 -嗯
- We need a confession. - Uh huh.
- From Cinda Canning? How do you propose we get that?
辛达·坎宁？你有何建议？
折磨她？我们能折磨她吗
- Torture? Can we torture her? [gasp]
查尔斯 把你的六角手风琴拿来
Charles, get your concertina
每当你思考你那十个最精彩的故事 都别忘了
and whatever you consider your 10 most interesting stories.
让我思考一下
- Hm, let me just muse on that,
uh, for a second. - Mm.
不 我们需要揭开辛达…
- No! We need to unravel Cinda
like a...
就像 老天 什么东西是能揭开的
Uh, like, oh, jeez...
What's a thing that unravels?
- Uh... - No, we just need to find the thing
我们需要找个东西揭开辛达真面目
that unravels Cinda, so she slips up
让她露出马脚 暴露她是凶手的事实
and reveals herself as the killer!
这个想法好
- Oh, that's good.
我们知道有一件事能让辛达发疯
- And what's the one thing we know drives Cinda crazy?
-毛衣 -毛衣能让辛达发疯？
- A sweater! - A sweater drives Cinda crazy?
不是 毛衣可以揭开 亲爱的 跟上节奏
- No, no, no. A sweater unravels, dear. Try to keep up, really.
谜团
- A mystery!
波比 她的助手能让她发疯
- Poppy! Her assistant, who drives her crazy.
不 我是说刚才没想起来那词 揭开谜团
- No, that's the word I was looking for. Unravels like a mystery.
- Oh no, no, no. I like sweater best.
-我更喜欢毛衣 -毛衣 对…
[overlapping arguing]
不 毛衣更好 因为你…
-谜团就有点… -你们俩中风了还是我中风了
- Have both of you had strokes or have I?
天啊
- God!
这感觉一点都不像大结局 是吧
This is really not feeling like a finale yet.
Is it?
♪ lively theme song playing ♪
♪ vocalizing ♪
《大楼里只有谋杀》
第二季第10集 我知道是谁干的
[bell ring, kitchen sounds] [soft music, diner chatter]
我有很多问题
I have so many questions. First off,
首先 你更喜欢被人叫贝基 还是波比
do you prefer Becky or Poppy?
或者是贝比 有一种似是而非的法式情调
Or would you prefer Boppy?
which has a certain je ne sais quois. - I can't do this.
-我做不到 -奥利弗 我们怎么说的
- Oliver, what did we agree on?
你和查尔斯负责说话
- You and Charles do the talking.
好吧 我们知道你为辛达工作
- Okay. We know you work for Cinda.
梅布已经解释过了你们的关系有多复杂
Mabel has explained how complicated that--
你有话就直说吧
- You can just cut to it.
我们怎么能击溃辛达 像塌陷的洞穴
- How can we get Cinda to crumble and cave like a...
crumbling cave?
-我没听懂 -我们怎么才能让辛达认罪
- Excuse me? - How do we get Cinda to confess?
她永远都不会 你们是认真的吗
- She'd never.
Are you serious?
你肯定知道什么事能刺激到她 让她变得脆弱
- You must know things that upset her, that might make her feel vulnerable.
当然
- I mean, sure. Human error, interruption,
人为错误 打断她 为她工作但跟她不像的员工
people who work for her but don't look like her.
最后这个我们注意到了
- Yeah, we noticed that one.
- Mm-hmm. - Are there things that disturb her,
有没有什么事能让她心烦意乱 攻破她的防线
that might break down her defenses?
她不喜欢番茄里面的部分
- She does not like the inside of a tomato?
理解
- Oh, I can see that.
番茄太吓人了
I'm terrified by tomatoes.
里面的部分？好惊悚
And the inside of them? [shudder]
Just awful.
好吧 我想我们可以在这上面做做文章
- Okay, I guess that's something we can work with.
-绝对的 -是吗
- Is it, though? What,
怎么做文章 邀请辛达到家里 给她做一道沙拉？
are we gonna invite Cinda over and make her a salad?
- Oh! Oh, this one's weird.
我想起了一件怪事
比害怕番茄还怪？
- The tomato was normal?
她很怕慢镜头
- Um, she's very afraid of slow-motion.
什么
- I'm sorry?
我跟辛达参加过一次超级碗派对
- I went to a Super Bowl party with Cinda,
每次有慢动作回放
and every time there was an instant replay, uh,
她就会发抖 然后头晕 然后开始哭泣
I saw her shiver, and then start to faint, and then cry a little bit.
因为慢镜头？
- Over the slow-motion?
-她不喜欢慢镜头 -好吧
- Slow-motion, she does not like it.
- Uh huh. - So, she's a true psychopath.
她还真是个神经病
你好 今天要吃什么
- Hello. What can I get for you today?
[buzzing]
糟了 是辛达
- Oh no, it's Cinda. [sigh]
《只有谋杀犯》大结局明天发布
The finale of Only Murderers
is dropping tomorrow. Um... [buzzing continues]
我要一份猪肝肠和橘子酱三明治 带走
Can I get a liverwurst and marmalade sandwich to go?
IVAN: Mm-hmm.
嗨 辛达 抱歉
- Hi, Cinda. I'm sorry. I'm on my way back.
我在往回赶了 火车误点了
There were train delays.
我的天啊
- Oh my god! - That's horrible.
太可怕了
猪肝肠和橘子酱？还有这种口味？
- Liverwurst and marmalade? Is that a thing?
这是店主妹妹最爱的三明治
- It's the owner's sister's favorite sandwich.
[Ivan laughs]
但邦尼看到我们菜单上有这款 觉得特别恶心
Bunny was so disgusted we had it on the menu,
她称之为怪胎食物
She called it "freak food."
[laugh]
很难不同意邦邦的见解
- Well, hard agree with Bun-Bun on that one.
-嘿 伊万 我的吐司呢 -来了
WOMAN: Hey, Ivan! Where's my toast?
-伙计们 -英式玛芬马上就好
- Guys... IVAN: English muffin, coming right up.
[phone ringing] - It's Detective Williams. Hang on.
是威廉姆斯警探 稍等
[answers phone]
辛达要发布最终集了
- Cinda's dropping the finale?
不难猜测她会公布谁是凶手
Not hard to guess who she's gonna name as the killer.
我们完了 我们今天就得把辛达抓起来
- We're fucked. We have got to put Cinda away today.
我们得动用我们所有的资源
- We need to rally our resources. - Right. That's right.
对 没错
嘿 伊万给我们点餐了吗
Hey, did Ivan ever take our order?
奥利弗 我们需要计划
- Oliver, we need a plan. - I agree.
我同意 但我们也得吃饭
We also need to eat.
她怎么说的
- What'd she say? Did Williams get any info off that knife?
威廉姆斯从那把刀上 得到了什么有用的线索吗
是的
- Yeah, she did.
Guys,
伙计们 我想我知道“14 萨维奇” 是什么意思了
I think I know what "14 Savage" means.
♪
我们来这儿做什么
[street noise] UMA: Why are we here?
我在组织遗物出售 但那让我很难过
I'm organizing the estate sale, but it's making me very sad.
她的植物都死了 而且为什么那只该死的鸟又回来了
All her plants are dying, and-- [room chatter]
Why is that damn bird back? [squawking]
那个可疑的邮件写道
That shady email just said, "be at Bunny's at 7:00
“如果你爱看好戏剧 想成为历史的一部分”
if you love good theater
“就在7点钟到邦尼家”
and/or want to be part of history."
我没看到蛋糕 邮件里说会提供蛋糕
- I don't see cake. The email said cake would be provided.
Cheap fucks.
小气鬼
我的打扮得体吗
- Am I dressed appropriately?
真的很难知道参加杀手揭晓派对 应该穿什么
It's really hard to know what to wear to a...
Killer Reveal Party.
是啊 “杀手揭晓派对” 意思是公布杀手身份的派对
- Uh, "killer reveal party"
meaning a party where a killer is revealed,
还是说这次揭晓派对很精彩
or a reveal party that's killer in nature?
我不知道 乔纳森 你负责帅帅的就好
- I don't know, Jonathan. Just be hot, okay?
朋友们 欢迎来到即将剧终的演出
- Welcome, friends! HOWARD: Oh, here we go.
OLIVER: To the show that's about to end.
因为我们已经查明是谁
For we have figured out who extinguished [door shuts]
the big, beautiful flame of our beloved Bunny Folger.
让我们亲爱的邦尼·福尔杰香消玉殒
好吧 到底是谁干的
- Alright, so who did it? - Who did it? Who did it?
谁干的
我要掐死那只鸟
I'm gonna strangle that bird.
-你以为我们会这么容易就告诉你们 -感觉是的
- You think we're just gonna tell you?
- Kind of felt like that, yeah. - Yeah. I mean, why else am I here?
是啊 不然我来这儿干吗
我们不是得告诉他们 他们也要参与进来吗
- Don't we kinda have to tell them if they're gonna be part of it?
- Must you poop on every party, Charles?
你一定要在每个派对上 都煞风景吗 查尔斯
我们就不能制造一点点悬念吗
Can't we have a little dramatic tension here?
奥利弗 她一小时后就到了 赶紧切入正题吧
- Oliver, she's gonna be here in an hour. Just move it along.
梅布 你是想急于求成 还是慢工出细活
- Mabel, we can do this production fast,
or we can do it well. What would you prefer?
你想要哪种
-急于求成 越快越好 -好的
- Fast. Do it fast.
- Okay. Well, then I will not take responsibility for the reviews.
那出现任何评价 都不关我事了
好的
Alright. Okay.
第一个问题 这里有人接受过戏剧训练吗
Uh, first question.
Who here has had any theater training?
我现在就在百老汇
- Well, I'm on Broadway right now.
-真的吗 -饰演鬣狗
- Really? - As a hyena. [giggle]
好吧
- Uh huh...
我原来为《约瑟夫和他的神奇彩衣》
- And I once auditioned for the part of Joseph
其中的约瑟夫一角试过镜
in Joseph And The Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat.
你的措辞听上去好像你没拿到那个角色
- The way you worded that makes it sound like you didn't get it.
是的
- That is correct.
但那与才华无关 不管我妈怎么说
But, it has nothing to do with talent,
despite what my mother said.
- Uh, Lester?
莱斯特？
我年轻的时候演过一些小打小闹的舞台剧
Uh, just a little light stage stuff when I was younger.
-真没想到 -对
- No shit! LESTER: Yeah,
我毕业于茱莉亚学院 最初是跟特雷西·莱特在百老汇登台演出
I graduated from Juilliard. Started out off-Broadway with Tracy Letts.
我们演对手戏 我向天发誓
We were rivals. Hand to God. CHARLES: And what happened,
如果你不介意我问一下的话 后来发生了什么事
if you don't mind me asking?
我不介意 我只是意识到 我真正想做的工作是门卫
- No, it's fine. I just realized that my true passion
was being a doorman, and I left the theater behind.
于是我就放弃了戏剧
真的吗
- Really?
你疯了吗 假的
- Are you nuts? No.
后来没人雇我了
I stopped getting hired, developed a drinking problem,
我开始酗酒 有一段时间无家可归
and was homeless for a while.
我差点死了 于是我戒了酒 接受了第一份我能找到的工作
Almost died, cleaned up,
took the first job I could get,
从此以后我就一直干着这份工作
and I've been stuck here ever since.
-天啊 -太悲惨了
- Jesus... - Oh, tragic!
多可惜啊
- Well, wasn't that a bummer? [awkward laugh]
言归正传 你们今天是来演戏的
Anyway! You're all here today
to play a part in manipulating a mastermind
要操纵一个犯罪主脑 在我们的摄像头视频中当场供认罪行
into a live confession on our...
cam show... Livestream. - Livestream.
-那叫直播 -直播
蛋糕在哪
- Where the hell is the fucking cake?
蛋糕在来的路上
- The cake is on its way!
但我们时间紧迫 蛋糕不是重点
But, this was very last minute, and this is not about the cake.
他们不打算给我们蛋糕了
- Ah, they chintzed on the cake!
我走了
[squawk] I'm leaving.
HOWARD: Come on, Jonathan. CHARLES: Wait!
等等
这事现在关系到我们每个人
This is about us right now!
邦尼的邻居们只有一次机会 让杀害她的凶手伏法
Bunny's fellow neighbors getting one shot
to bring her killer to justice!
- And we all really need your help.
我们真的需要你们的帮助
好吧
- Fine.
但邦尼会从92号街的谢尔曼烘焙定蛋糕
But, Bunny would have ordered the cake from Sherman's on 92nd.
-确实 -好的
- True.
- Okay. We only have an hour.
我们只有一个小时了
[sigh] And if we pull this off,
如果我们成功的话
我向这个房间里的每个人发誓
I swear to each and every person in this room
你们想吃什么蛋糕 查尔斯都给你们买
that Charles will buy you the cake of your choice!
♪
[knocking]
好了 开始了
- Okay. Here we go.
我为了这事错过了家长会
- I'm missing a parent teacher conference for this,
所以你的认罪最好值得我跑这一趟 我孩子的老师特别帅气性感
so your confession better be good.
My kid's teacher is crazy hot.
[shuts door] - Who said anything about a confession?
谁说要认罪了
你说你要当场公布谋杀犯的身份
- Well, you said you were gonna reveal the murderer live,
and you're the murderer. So, by my math,
而你就是谋杀犯
所以根据我的推理 这就相当于是认罪了 莫拉小姐
that makes this a confession, Ms. Mora.
你真的要这么做吗
- [quiet]: Are you really doing this? - Mm-hmm.
这是什么情况
- What the hell is this?
我们破案了
♪
这是杀手揭晓派对
- It's a killer reveal party. [laugh]
是揭晓杀手身份的派对
- As in a party that reveals a killer,
还是说揭晓派对本身很精彩
or a reveal party that's going to be killer.
看吧 有歧义
- [quiet]: See? It is confusing. - Shh...
一切都会解释清楚的
- It will all be explained.
辛达 我们打开了录像设备
And Cinda, we have our recording devices on,
所以你也许也想打开你的
so you may wanna turn on yours.
我有助理做这些事 波比 开始拍摄
- I have a girl for that. Poppy, please start recording everything.
你需要我给他们戴上随身麦克风 还是用吊杆麦克风就好
- Would you like me to wire anyone or just use the boom?
- Uh, just record all the smart things I say
记录下我的妙语连珠 和他们愚蠢的发言就行了
and all the dumb shit that they grunt.
天啊 我好激动
[through gritted teeth]: Oh my god!
Okay, go ahead.
好了 开始吧
欢迎来到我们的杀手揭晓派对 我们将揭示杀害邦尼的凶手的真实身份
- Welcome to our killer reveal party!
Where we will reveal Bunny's killer.
与此同时 这派对也很精彩
It's also a killer party, simultaneously.
-好吧 所以我们都是对的 -两种理解
- Oh. Okay, so we were both right. [overlapping murmuring]
-那是… -玩了个双关
- Double entendre. [door opens]
我要很遗憾地告诉各位 凶手就在我们中间
CHARLES: And it gives me no pleasure
to inform you
that the killer is here, [door shuts]
就在这个房间里
in this very room.
但不可能 我们中的一个是凶手？ 告诉我这不是真的
- [bad acting]: [gasp] But that can't be! One of us?
Please say it's not true!
霍华德 太过了
- Howard. [shushing] Bring it down.
我们先来回顾下我们都知道些什么
- Let's remind ourselves of what we know.
邦尼的最后一日很平常 她在考虑做出改变
Bunny had a very normal last day of life.
She was contemplating a change. A move, to Florida.
搬去佛罗里达州
去他的佛罗里达！
- Fuck Florida! [squawk]
我们三个那晚见过她
- The three of us saw her that very night.
她想寻求陪伴 寻求朋友
[inaudible] She was looking for companionship.
A friend.
但我们做了什么
But, what did we do? - OLIVER: Bye-bye.
我们拒绝了她
We rejected her. [shuts door]
把她赶走了 回到了她自己的公寓
We sent her away,
back to her apartment.
那里有人在等着她
MABEL: Where someone was waiting for her.
♪
那个人逼迫邦尼来到我的公寓 好嫁祸于我
[struggling, slice] Someone who forced Bunny into my apartment
to frame me,
之后用奥利弗的刀和我的毛衣针杀害了她
then stabbed her with Oliver's knife
and my knitting needle, then escaped
并逃到了他们早就知晓的 阿卡尼亚秘密通道
[thunder] into the Arconia's secret passageways
that they knew about,
并利用这些秘密通道
then used those secret passageways
将凶器放到查尔斯的公寓
to plant the murder weapon in Charles' apartment,
还有一幅从邦尼公寓被偷走的
along with a very valuable painting
of his nude father they stole from Bunny's apartment...
画着他裸体父亲的价值连城的画作
天啊 我们真要把这些公之于众吗
Jesus, is this what we're really telling people?
信息量是挺大的 我们可以在排练时 删减掉一些
- It's a lot. We could have tightened it up in rehearsal.
但到底是谁想要陷害三个无辜的人呢
- But, who... had an interest in framing
three... innocent... people!?
是你
You did! - Me!?
-我？ -抱歉 我转晕了
- Sorry! I got disoriented! You did!
是你
[scoff] - Cinda Canning killed Bunny Folger.
辛达·坎宁杀害了邦尼·福尔杰
她是如何掩饰罪行的
And how did she cover her tracks?
通过一个她几年前 在俄克拉荷马认识的一个黑警
With the help of a crooked cop she met years ago in Oklahoma.
[billiards sounds] [bar chatter]
♪
你怎么知道克雷普斯的事
- How did you know about Kreps?
[gasps] OLIVER: Are you kidding?
你开玩笑吗
The sexual energy between you two was obvious.
你们两个之间的性能量太明显了
我想多说几句 但这是面向家庭观众的 犯罪播客节目
I'd say more,
but this is a family murder podcast.
辛达·坎宁并不是一个擅长破案的播客主
- Cinda Canning is not a great podcaster who solves murders.
她擅长的是编造和包装故事
MABEL: She's a hack who makes them up and packages them.
这次她想逃脱的是杀人
And this time, she tried to get away with a doozy.
哇
- Wow.
我真的很欣赏这个精彩的开场
Really enjoyed the spelling it all out.
很像每集最后会公布真相的《史努比》 很可爱
Very end of a Scooby Doo episode. Very cute.
但有个小问题
One little problem, though.
我为什么要杀害一个素昧谋面的老妇人
Why would I want to kill an old woman I never met?
你见过她 坎宁女士
- You met her, Ms. Canning.
我有大楼进出记录
I have the logbooks.
在邦尼死前 你经常来这里 不是吗
You were actually here a lot before Bunny died, weren't you?
我是在追踪蒂姆·科诺案件的调查情况
- I was keeping tabs on the Tim Kono investigation.
你杀了她 你残忍地杀害了她
- You killed her.
You murdered her with a violent hand.
你谋杀了一位善良和蔼的老妇人
You murdered a sweet old lady
who...
她是我的朋友
She was my friend!
她是我唯一的朋友 可你却夺走了她的性命
She was my only friend,
and you took her!
为什么
And why!?
为了播客吗
For a podcast!?
为什么
[emotional]: Why?
Why...
天啊 他太棒了
Oh, Jesus, he's wonderful.
♪ I love my coat of many colors ♪
♪ I just love my coat of many colors ♪
霍华德 别唱了
- Howard, no.
[frustrated grunt]
我没有动机 我为什么要做这种事
- There is literally no motive here.
Why would I have done any of this?
这个问题
- [slow-motion]: What...
问得
an...
excellent...
太好了
question...
是的
OLIVER [slow-motion]: It... is...
indeed...
你们怎么突然开始做慢动作了
- Why are you moving in slow motion?
谁在做慢动作
[Cinda panting] CHARLES [slow-motion]: Who's... going...
slow?
谁 我们吗
OLIVER [slow-motion]: Who... us?
[whimper]
[tenants speaking in slow-motion]
♪
[slow-motion continues]
-停下 我…我要走了 -好吧 停
- Stop it! Stop it! I-I'm leaving!
- Alright, stop!
[cart rattling]
天啊 这是什么
- Oh god, what is that?
你签署了一份价值三千亿美元的播客交易
- So, you sign a big, juicy
$30 million podcast deal.
Problem is,
问题是 你并没有一个足够精彩的故事
[grabs knife] you don't have a juicy story to podcast.
So, you go looking
于是你亲手设计了一个 孤单的老妇人
to invent one about a lonely
old woman who gets murdered
在高档公寓大楼被谋杀的故事
in a big... fancy...
apartment building. - No... No...
老实说 这个故事还不够好
- Honestly,
not that great.
[squishing] [gag, whimper]
除非凶手是三个一线大咖
Unless, the three people who did the murdering
are three A-list celebrities!
[laugh]
♪
抱歉 我以为你是在搞笑
- Oh. Sorry.
I thought you were being funny.
我们是不是让你很愤怒 坎宁女士
- Are we getting under your skin, Ms. Canning?
承认是你干的吧 承认吧
OLIVER: Admit you did it.
Admit you did it! - [squawk] Admit it! Admit it!
承认吧
别做梦了 我不会认罪的
- Forget it! And I'm not confessing anything
因为…
because... because...
因为什么？
- Because why!?
因为她不是凶手
- Because she didn't do it.
- Mabel, we're so close. What are you doing?
梅布 我们就差一点了 你干什么
我在破解谋杀案
- I'm solving a murder.
♪
她才是凶手
She did it.
[gasps, murmuring]
不好意思 什么
- Excuse me, what?
这是一位新近加入的艺术家的作品
- This is the work of an artist
who just came into the picture recently.
你的画廊需要“新鲜血液” 这不是你自己说的吗
Your gallery needed new energy. Wasn't that what you said?
原来 你是要把我的悲惨遭遇做成艺术
Turns out, you were making art
from my tragedy. So, why not frame me
所以 何不陷害我 让你的作品更上一层楼呢
and up the value of your art?
这是计划中的吗
Is this all part of the plan? - I'm really not sure anymore.
我已经不知道了
太过分了 老实说 我们之前不是已经解除了这个误会吗
- I am outraged. And frankly, haven't we been down this road before?
抱歉 这个人是谁
- Sorry. Who is this person?
能让她大点声吗
And can we get her to dial the accent down a little bit?
如果我都听不到 那广大的美国中部 怎么能听得到
I mean, if I can't understand a word, how's Middle America gonna get it?
你真的很有魅力 爱丽丝 而且吻技一流
MABEL: You're a real charmer, Alice.
And a hell of a kisser.
劲爆
MARV: Nice. [snapping]
但你也是个骗子…
- But, you're also a liar.
[unfolding]
和杀人凶手
And a killer.
- Huh.
[slow clap] Bravo, Mabel. Bravo indeed.
厉害啊 梅布 真有你的
这么久以来 我还以为你是个 画技只有学龄前儿童水平的
Here, all this time, I was thinking you were just a bore
with the drawing skills of a toddler.
无聊透顶的人
泡菜餐馆的那个人是你
- It was you at the Pickle Diner,
求邦尼把她那幅罗斯·库伯的画卖给你
begging Bunny for her Rose Cooper painting.
可她开价一千四百万
But, she wanted 14 million for it.
一千四百万买《萨维奇》
14 for Savage.
有点超出你的预算了 对吗
That was a little out of your price range, wasn't it?
你这个资质平庸的贱人
- [quiet]: You talentless, smug bitch.
天啊 是她干的 她被逮住了
- Holy shit, she did it. She got her.
[slice] - No!
-不 -不要
[gasps]
[stab] [scream, gasps]
[overlapping yelling]
-抓住她 -查尔斯
♪
放开我
[Alice yelling] - Oh! Oh!
-天啊 查尔斯 -放开我
Oh! - Charles! Charles!
放开我
- Get off me! - Hold her down!
按住她的胳膊 按住她
[yelling continues] [groan]
[smash]
-对 是911吗 这里有人被捅了 -我的天啊
UMA: Yes, 911? There's been a stabbing!
对 地址是阿卡尼亚 他在流血
Yes, at the Arconia! Yes, he's bleeding!
-查尔斯 -查尔斯
MABEL: Charles? Charles! OLIVER: Charles! Oh my... Oh jeez...
-天啊 -查尔斯
你没事的 伙计 你不会有事的
You're okay, buddy. You're okay.
[Mabel and Oliver panting]
[gasp] [sniffle]
-不 -不
Oh... [sob]
Charles...
[Mabel and Oliver crying]
天啊
老天爷 告诉我你都录下来了
- Jesus Christ.
Please tell me you got all that.
♪
[both crying]
放开我
ALICE: Unhand me! [Mrs. Gambolini squawking]
你没事的 干柏林妮小姐 别害怕
[struggling] HOWARD: It's okay, Mrs. Gambolini.
Don't be scared. [calm squawk]
这只鸟见过太多惨剧了 乔纳森
This bird has seen too much, Jonathan.
警察和救护车三分钟后赶到
- Police and ambulance are three minutes out.
[hushed room chatter]
太可怕了
我很抱歉 梅布 为发生的一切
CINDA: I'm so sorry, Mabel.
For all of it.
可怜的孩子
You poor kid.
But, what you just did...
但你刚才所做的事
I mean...
可恶 你真的很棒
Shit, you were incredible.
你是非常称职的调查员
You are one hell of an investigator.
我正需要你这样的员工 我…
I could use someone like you on my staff.
我是说 我…
I mean, hell, I...
你觉得你可以拥有自己的播客
I think you could have your own podcast.
别 千万不要
- Oh, don't even. Don't you even...
[squawking] - Poppy?
波比？
什么
- [laugh] What... [frustrated sigh]
这只是运气好
This was pure luck!
没有什么证据能把那个澳大利亚女孩 跟邦尼的谋杀案联系起来
Th-there is absolutely nothing
that ties this Australian girl to Bunny's murder.
-什么都没有 -我是英国人 你个蠢货
Nothing.
- I'm English, you twat.
- Ah choo!
上帝保佑
- Bless you. - Thank you.
谢谢
为什么梅布能有自己的播客
Why does Mabel get a podcast?
因为她漂亮？
Because she's pretty?
因为她很勇敢 跟传言中的凶手约会？
Because she boldly dated the supposed killer?
我为你做了一切
I do everything for you.
我给你买午饭
I get your lunch, and I respond to all your mail,
我回复你所有的信件
给你取干洗的衣服 再从洗衣店拿回来
and I pick up your dry cleaning, and I drop off your dry cleaning,
在你家和洗衣店之间来回折腾
and I pick up your dry cleaning, and I drop off your dry cleaning, and--
你为什么就不能穿可以水洗的衣服呢
Why don't you just wear something that you can wash!?
而且我跟你提过罗斯·库伯画作的点子 但你讲了个放屁的笑话
And I told you about the Rose Cooper art,
and you made a flying fart joke.
我跟你说过…
I told you all--
Ah choo! CINDA: Okay, Poppy,
好吧 波比 你知道我的规矩
you know my rule. Two sneezes means
当着我的面打喷嚏 你要自我隔离一周
you need to self-quarantine for a week.
波比 你为什么告诉辛达罗斯·库伯的事
MABEL: Poppy?
Why'd you tell Cinda about Rose Cooper?
♪
我认为那是个做播客的好题材 辛达不感兴趣
- It was an idea for a podcast.
Cinda was not interested...
但你很有兴趣 对邦尼的那幅画也很感兴趣
- But, you were,
and in that painting that Bunny owned.
- Ah choo!
你是对什么东西过敏吗 比如说 干柏林妮小姐？
- Do you have some kind of allergy?
To Mrs. Gambolini perchance?
- Ah choo!
[squawk]
太奇怪了 凶手逃离案发现场时 也打了喷嚏
- It's so strange.
The killer sneezed when fleeing the crime scene.
[sneezing]
对臭烘烘的鸟毛过敏又不是犯罪
- It's not a crime to be allergic to rancid bird molting.
怎么 你们不会是相信了
And what? You're gonna believe some-- some young girl
那个藏在你们墙壁里的小女孩的话吧
that's hiding in your walls? [scoff]
只有凶手知道那天晚上有个女孩 藏在墙壁里
- Only the killer could have known there was a girl hiding in the walls that night.
- And her name is Lucy.
她叫露西
而你叫贝基
CINDA: And yours...
is Becky.
谁告诉你的
- Who told you that?
我们
CHARLES: We did.
[screaming]
[wail]
♪
I wasn't stabbed.
我没有被捅 都是演的
It's all theater.
我们从今天下午就盯上你了
- We've been onto you since this afternoon!
- We all have.
我们都是
我不明白这是怎么回事
- I don't understand what's happening! CINDA: It's over, kiddo.
结束了 孩子
我知道你在俄克拉荷马跟我玩的把戏
I know the game you played with me in Oklahoma,
他们知道你在这栋高价公寓里 跟他们玩的把戏
and they know the game you played with them
in this overpriced building.
我只有一次是真晕 剩下的都是装的
- And I only real fainted once.
The other times were acting.
我只是想制作一档优秀的播客 让辛达注意到我
- [Southern accent]: I just wanted to make a good podcast.
I just wanted Cinda to notice me.
但事情从一开始就出了差错
Things went wrong right from the start.
从我给你们发信息叫你们离开的那晚
Right from that night that I texted you
to get out of the building, and you came back to your apartment.
可你又回去了你的公寓
[beep] [muffled door opening]
查尔斯 奥利弗 梅布 快离开大楼
[muffled door shut]
你是怎么想明白这一切的
How'd you figure it out?
[phone ringing] - It's Detective Williams. Hang on.
是威廉姆斯警探 稍等
[answers phone]
-嘿 -嘿
Hey. WILLIAMS [phone]: Hey.
我从凶器上提取到了DNA 唾液
So, I got DNA off the murder weapon. Saliva.
但是听好了
But, get this.
唾液的主人是一个远在其他州的 死去的女孩
It belongs to a dead girl
from way the hell out of state.
让我猜猜 俄克拉荷马州？
- Let me guess.
Oklahoma.
♪
你怎么知道的
- How the hell did you know that?
我想我知道“14 萨维奇”是什么意思了
- I think I know what "14 Savage" means.
14号三明治 猪肝肠和橘子酱
三明治
- Sandwich... [bell ding]
14号三明治？ 猪肝肠和橘子酱 带走
IVAN: 14 sandwich? Liverwurst and marmalade to go.
是我的
- That's me.
[door opens]
[door shuts]
问题是
- The thing is,
在我成为人们街头巷尾热议的女孩前
before I became one of the most talked about people in the country...
我过着普通的生活
I had a pretty ordinary life.
[bang]
[muffled police radio chatter]
如果你假设大多数普通人的生活 都很悲惨的话
Ordinary, that is, if you assume
most ordinary people are pretty miserable.
[muffled bang, click]
Which I assume is a pretty safe assumption.
我想这个假设是十分合理的
♪
[inaudible]
波比
贝基·巴特勒想办法利用她自己的故事
CHARLES: Once Becky Butler found the way
to use her own story to get a job
在她的偶像辛达·坎宁那里 谋得一份工作时…
with her hero, Cinda Canning... [door shuts]
你想要什么
- Uh, what exactly do you want?
我想要一份工作 坎宁女士
- I would like a job, Ms. Canning.
CHARLES: ...she thought she'd be home free.
她以为她可以高枕无忧了
她甚至找到了一个帮手
CINDA: She even found someone that was willing to help her.
但是一开始 如同所有最终分崩离析的事
Though, at first, like so many things that go bad,
都是因为爱
it was just about love.
于是她得寸进尺 策划了更为大胆的“纽约”故事
CHARLES: So, she went the extra mile
[muffled chatter] and plotted a bigger New York story.
-我不知道我能不能行 -你当然行
- Yes, you can. She's old. And mean.
她又老又刻薄
这是你应得的 是我们应得的
You deserve this. We both do.
你能出名 我能升职
You get to be famous, I get a promotion, [laugh]
我们就能从这个破房子搬走
and we get to move out of this sweaty shit-box. Yes.
-是的 -你能行
[kiss] You got this. [indistinct] - I deserve it. I deserve it.
-这是我应得的 -这是你他妈应得的
-这是我应得的 -这是你应得的
[giggling]
Ooh! Did I tell you about the secret passageways I found?
我跟你说过我发现的秘密通道吗
KREPS: What? Fuck, I fucking love you.
什么 我太爱你了
就这样 另一个谜团破解了
- And with that, another mystery solved.
《大楼里只有谋杀》最终集…
So one last time,
for Only Murders In The Building...
《大楼里只有谋杀犯》最终集…
- And for Only Murderers In The Building...
我是奥利弗·帕特曼
- I'm Oliver Putnam.
我是梅布·莫拉
- I'm Mabel Mora.
我是查尔斯·海登·萨维奇
And I'm Charles-Haden Savage.
我是辛达·坎宁
- And Cinda Canning. Thanks again to our sponsor
再次感谢我们的赞助商 格特淡奶
Gut Milk Lite. It's got all the flavor of Gut Milk
拥有格特牛奶的全部口味 且没有无法解释的杂质
and none of the unexplained crunch.
- [sigh] Wow.
-哇 两起谋杀案 一波未平一波又起 -是啊
Two murders back to back. - Yep.
现在我们可以像其他人一样聊天了 而不是开口必提谋杀案
- Now, we can start talking to each other like people
and not just about murders. - Right.
是啊
[sigh] [throat clear]
♪ On The Sunny Side Of The Street by Keely Smith ♪
[street noise] [distant siren]
- Ah. Thank you.
谢谢
[set chatter]
-好吧 轮椅在哪 -你没看舞台说明吗
- Okay, where's the wheelchair? - Didn't you read the stage directions?
没有 我就一句台词
- No, I have one line. - Charles,
查尔斯 你的观众反馈好得不得了
your test scores are off the charts!
公司想让你立刻从轮椅上下来
The network wants you out of the wheelchair immediately,
and your dementia is in remish.
你的老年痴呆也好了
哈利路亚 这是上帝显灵了吧
- Hallelujah! It's a miracle cure!
- [giggle] Nice. You got de-dementia'd.
恭喜你治好了老年痴呆
谢谢 小露
CHARLES: Thanks, Luce. - Last looks!
最后补个妆
- Oop.
欢迎回到直立行走的世界
- Well, welcome back
to the world of the upright. - Thanks, Joy.
谢谢 乔伊
- Hm.
你很帅 查尔斯
Looking good, Charlie.
[set chatter continues]
嘿 乔伊
- Hey, Joy. - Yeah?
什么事
♪ Life can be... ♪
- Uh...
[grunt]
♪ On the sunny side of the street ♪
你要约我出去吗
- Are you asking me out on a date?
[exhale]
什么时候
For when?
[exhale]
你是说今晚吗
Are you suggesting tonight?
对
- [choked]: Yes.
♪ But, I'm not afraid ♪
查理 我终于等到了 你总算说出口了
- Oh, Charlie.
Finally, you got it out.
♪ Crossed over ♪
♪ If I never have a cent ♪
天啊
Jesus. God.
♪ I'll be rich as ♪
♪ Rockefeller ♪
♪ Gold dust at my feet ♪
你真的这么做了 你把这里翻新了
- You're doing it. You're actually renovating.
也是时候了
- Well, it is about time.
这会融入新设计吗
- And does this become integrated into a new design?
我呢
And do I?
- Uh, no. But,
不会
但你可以拿个滚刷 帮我一起刷
you could grab a roller and help, please.
♪ Direct your feet ♪
♪ The sunny side ♪
♪ Can't you hear ♪
♪ A pitter-pat? ♪
嘿
- Hey, hey!
♪ Oh, that happy ♪
嘿
OLIVER: Hey! - Hey, girl.
看看你 从巫师和芒奇津人之地 胜利归来了
- Look at you. Fresh from his triumph in the land of witches and munchkins.
- Uh, triumph, I don't know about that, but we survived.
胜利 我不敢说 但我们活下来了
-是啊 -那只…
- Yeah. - Now, um, where is...
你现在叫它什么来着
W-what are you calling her now?
妈妈G？对
- Oh, Mama G! Yes, yes, yes. She's, uh, right here.
它就在这儿 看上去有点憔悴
She's just looking a little pekid to me.
好了 我们来看看
- Alright. Let's take a look.
维尼最先注意到的
- Winnie noticed it first. WILL: So, you decided to keep her, huh?
你决定留下它了？
我只是…维尼跟它处出感情了 所以…
- Well, I just... Winnie's grown awfully attached, so...
[squawk] [shuts gate]
[quiet wing flapping]
威利 有件事我要告诉你
Willie, th-there's something...
I-I need to tell you.
我之前没有跟你说实话
S-something I...
haven't been honest about. Uh...
爸爸
- Dad.
如果你不是我父亲 我不知道还有谁能当我的父亲
If you're not my father, then I don't know what a father is.
明白吗
You hear me?
你怎么知道的
- How did you know? - Come on.
拜托 我知道你所有的破绽
I know all your tells.
[soft laugh, sigh]
我好爱你
- I love you so much.
[phone ringing, buzzing]
你要接吗
- You gonna get that?
不接 现在不行
- No, no, no, not now. [laugh]
[squawk] [ringing continues]
骗谁呢 赶紧接吧
- Who are we kidding? J-just take the call.
我想…
- Well, I guess... [laugh] You know,
赶紧接完得了 谁知道是什么事
just to get it out of the way. You never know.
是唐娜 我的一个制片人朋友
Oh, it's Donna. Producer friend of mine. [answers phone]
嘿 唐娜 有何贵干
Hey, Donna.
To what do I owe this... [Mrs. Gambolini squawking]
不 我知道 我确实欠你很多钱
No, I know. I actually do owe you a lot of money, but is that...
你是为了这个打电话吗
Is that why you're calling?
[food bowl rattling]
真的吗
Oh, really? [gate creaks shut]
导演放鸽子了还是怎么
What, did the director fall out or something?
百老汇
Broadway?
♪
一年后首演？
It opens in a year. Well, yes.
好啊 我想我可以…我是完美人选
I-I think I-I would be perfect for that.
主演是谁
And who's the star?
♪
真的假的
Really!?
一年后
[knocking] Ben?
本
所有人首演时都会紧张 我可以跟你聊聊
Everyone gets opening night jitters!
I can talk you through it!
更衣室 本·格伦罗伊
我没事
- I'm good.
[snort]
[theater chatter] OLIVER: Alright...
听着 我没事 好吗 我会大放异彩的
- Hey, look, I'm good, okay? I'm gonna rock this place.
你应该去找另外一个家伙聊 那个笨蛋
It's the other guy you need to talk to. Fuckbag.
不 好吧 我跟他聊过了…
- No, no. So, okay, so I did talk to him, and--
他道歉了吗
- Uh huh. Did he apologize?
你也知道 发生了很多事 但是…
- Well, you know, a lot has gone on, but...
这是我的建议
Look, this is what I suggest.
利用这股愤怒
Use it, okay?
让你们俩的怨气渗透进今晚的表演
Let the tension seep in between you two tonight as a color.
- Okay, so, like, then I can kill him?
好吧 就像是 我可以杀了他
因为我真干得出来 奥利弗 我警告你
Because I just might, Oliver. I'm warning you it.
你瞧 就是这个效果
- No, see, now, that is an interesting color.
- Places! Break a leg, Ben. [snort]
各就各位
祝你好运 本
我也可以敲断他一条腿
- That's a pretty good option, too.
- Oh. [laugh] Well, anyway. Okay, so I just--
总之 好吧 我就是…
[trilling] Fun out there...
希望你玩得开心
[trill]
[theater chatter continues] [coughing]
- Ah...
[cough]
[footsteps]
今晚祝你好运
- Good luck tonight.
- Huh. Thanks.
谢谢
“祝你好运”在剧院里是诅咒
- "Good luck" is a curse in the theater.
我知道
- I know that.
你以为我不知道吗
- What, y-you don't think I know that?
我是出于礼貌才没戳穿你
I just didn't mention it
to be polite to you, you piece of shit.
你这个笨蛋
嘿
- Hey. Hey. [instruments tuning up]
我们要一起合作两个半小时
We got two and a half hours to get through. If I can do it, you can, too.
如果我能做到 你也能
我是专业的 好吧 你不用担心我
- I'm the pro here. Alright, you don't have to worry about me.
放聪明点 离她远点
- Be smart.
Stay away from her.
为什么 不然你能怎样
- Why?
What are you gonna do? - Ben...
本 我知道你干过什么
I know what you did.
[scoff]
[theater chatter] [instruments continue tuning up]
嘿 妹子
- Hey, girl. LUCY: Oh.
-真不敢相信 -是啊
I can't believe this. - Right? What a year, huh?
这一年过的真是
- Yeah. Well,
对我来说 只要没有谋杀案 就是好年景
any year without a murder is a good one in my book.
好了 系紧安全带
- Okay. Fasten your seat belts.
[grunt] Hey, honey.
-嘿 -嘿 亲爱的
-我太为你骄傲了 -谢谢
- So proud of you. - Thank you, thank you, thank you...
[sniff, throat clear]
[chatter quiets down]
[applause]
[cheering] [bell tolling]
[applause dies down] [birds chirping]
是什么让我变成黑夜中的野兽
- What turned me into a creature of the night.
[raven cawing] [wolf howling]
让我来告诉你
Let me tell you.
[quiet metallic sounds] [wind blowing]
[distant ship horn]
[thud]
♪
一个…
A cre--
[heavy breathing]
[gasping]
怎么回事
让我…
Let me t-- Ooh...
救命
[high, weak]: Help me...
[audience gasps]
- Somebody! Anybody!
来人啊
[audience murmuring]
他不动了
- He's not moving!
♪ crescendo ♪
开什么玩笑
- You've gotta be fucking kidding me.
♪ dramatic yodeling ♪
贝基·巴特勒在哪
♪ yodeled theme song ♪
《俄克拉荷马不太欧克》 辛达·坎宁
演出和舞台剧 兰索夫剧院
♪ yodel solo ♪
字幕翻译：肖雪
♪ end of solo ♪